Evangelos Ladakis

Curriculum Vitae

Greece City, Heraklion ⊠ ladakis@csd.uoc.gr , ladakis@ics.forth.gr '• csd.uoc.gr/~ladakis Date Of Birth 18/12/1989

Interests & Ambitions

parallel programming, security in operating systems, malware analysis, attacks and defenses in general in Computer Science. Final goal is the specialization in security systems and either working in a company which develops security products like anti-malware/ anti-viruses either in a research foundation.

Education

Sep. 2013 – Present **Master Candidate in Distributed Computing Systems**, *Computer Science Department*, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, Heraklion.

Supervisors Professor Evangelos Markatos & Principal Researcher Sotiris Ioanidis

Short Term Scholar Assistant Professor George Portokalidis Supervisor

Sep. 2007 – July 2013 **B.Sc in Computer Science**, Computer Science Department, University of Crete, Heraklion.

Work Experience

May 2015 Took part in domestic cyber exercise "Panoptis" as a member of FORTH-ICS Distributed Computing Systems lab

Jan. 2015 – June 2015 **Teacher Assistant**, Computer Science Department, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, Heraklion Crete. cs240-Data Structures

Sep. 2014 – Jan. 2015 **Teacher Assistant**, Computer Science Department, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, Heraklion Crete. cs345-Operating Systems

July 2014 – Sep. 2014 Graduate Research Assistant, STEVENS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, Hoboken, New Jersey, U.S.

Short Term Scholar

March 2014 Took part in Cyber Defence Exercise "Cyber Protector 2014" as a member of FORTH-ICS Distributed Computing Systems lab

Feb. 2014 – July 2014 **Teacher Assistant**, Computer Science Department, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, Heraklion Crete. cs335-Computer Networks

Oct. 2013 Took part in domestic Security Contest of Japan "IWSEC 2013" as a member of FORTH-ICS Distributed Computing Systems lab

Sep. 2013 – Feb. 2014 **Teacher Assistant**, Computer Science Department, UNIVERSITY OF CRETE, Heraklion Crete. cs252-Object Oriented Programming JAVA

July 2013 - Present Graduate Research Assistant, FORTH-ICS, Heraklion Crete.

Jan. 2013 Took part in domestic cyber exercise "Panoptis" as a member of FORTH-ICS Distributed Computing Systems lab

Sep. 2012 – July 2013 Undergraduate Research Assistant, FORTH-ICS, Heraklion Crete.

Scholarships

July 2014 - Sep. 2014 SysSec Internship Scholarship

Technical skills

Very good knowledge of C programming language

Very Good knowledge of NVIDIA CUDA programming language

Good knowledge of JAVA programming language

Knowledge of $x86\ {\rm ARCHITECTURE}$ assembly language

Knowledge of reverse engineering tools, IDA PRO scripting language

Experienced with Sql-injection, Buffer Overflow, DDoS attacks and analysis, port scanning attacks and analysis, keylogger malwares and malware analysis

Experienced with Linux Kernel and Windows Kernel programming

Projects

Sep. 2012 – April 2013 *Malware In GPU* April 2013 – Dec. 2014 *GPU Disassembler* Graduation Thesis

Master Thesis

Conferences & Workshops

Apr. 2013 EuroSys Conference 2013 April 2013, Prague, Czech Republic.

presented: "You can Type, but You Can't Hide: A stealthy GPU-based Keylogger" at EuroSec 2013 Workshop which is part of EuroSys

July 2014 DIMACS Workshop on Multicore and Cryptography July 2014, Hoboken, NJ USA.

Attended

Sep. 2014 **2014 AT&T Cyber Security Conference September 2014, Manhattan, NY USA**.

Attended

Sep. 2015 Information Secutiry Conference September 2015, Trondheim, Norway.

presented: "GPU-Disasm: A GPU-Based X86 Disassembler"

Publications

"You can Type, but You Can't Hide: A stealthy GPU-based Keylogger".

Evangelos Ladakis, Lazaros Koromilas, Giorgos Vasiliadis, Michalis Polychronakis, Sotiris Ioannidis. In Proceedings of the 6th European Workshop on System Security (EuroSec). April 2013, Prague, Czech Republic

"GPU-Disasm: A GPU-Based X86 Disassembler".

Evangelos Ladakis, Giorgos Vasiliadis, Michalis Polychronakis, Sotiris Ioannidis, Georgios. In proceedings of the Information Security Conference (ISC), Trondheim, Norway, September 2015

Languages

Greek Native

English Intermediate

Conversationally fluent